Guide to the Kuntu Repertory Theatre Records, 1973-2013 CTC.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Production Records, c. 1947-2013; I.
  - Pre and Post Production Records, 1975-2013; 7.
    - Season 2001-2002, Sun Rising on the Hill District
    - Season 2001-2002, Sun Rising on the Hill District Study Guide
    - Season 2001-2002, Vo-Du MacBeth
    - Season 2001-2002, Whispers Want to Holler
    - Season 2001-2002, Whispers Want to Holler Study Guide
    - Season 2001-2002, Whispers Want to Holler Contracts
    - Season 2002-2003
    - Season 2002-2003, Study Guides
    - Season 2002-2003, Ashes to Africa
    - Season 2002-2003, Ashes to Africa Contracts
    - Season 2002-2003, Ashes to Africa Expenses
    - Season 2002-2003, Ashes to Africa Study Guide
    - Season 2002-2003, Ashes to Africa Tickets for Kids
    - Season 2002-2003, Crawford Grill Presents Billie Holiday & Mahalia Jackson South Africa Tour
    - ## Season 2002-2003, Cryin' Shame
    - Season 2002-2003, Cryin' Shame Expenses
    - Season 2002-2003, Cryin' Shame Study Guide
    - Season 2002-2003, Difficult Days Ahead in a Blaze
    - Season 2002-2003, Difficult Days Ahead in a Blaze Contracts and Expenses
    - Season 2002-2003, Difficult Days Ahead in a Blaze Study Guide
    - Season 2002-2003, Difficult Days Ahead in a Blaze Ticket Sales
    - Season 2002-2003, Hieroglyphic Graffiti
    - Season 2002-2003, Hieroglyphic Graffiti Study Guide
    - Season 2002-2003, Keepers of the Dream
    - Season 2002-2003, A Liberating Prayer: A Love Song for Mumia
    - Season 2002-2003, A Liberating Prayer: A Love Song for Mumia Contracts and Expenses
    - Season 2002-2003, A Liberating Prayer: A Love Song for Mumia Study Guide
    - Season 2002-2003, Lift Every Voice and Sing
    - Season 2002-2003, Lift Every Voice and Sing Contracts
    - Season 2002-2003, What'd You Do Today by Billie Joe
    - Season 2003-2004
    - Season 2003-2004, Costuming
    - Season 2003-2004, Research, 2001
    - Season 2003-2004, Research
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One Contracts
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One Contracts, Expenses, Sales
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One Costumes and Research
    - Season 2003-2004, Buffalo Soldiers: Plus One Study Guide
    - Season 2003-2004, Dark Cowgirls and Praire Queens
    - Season 2003-2004, Dark Cowgirls and Praire Queens Study Guide
    - Season 2003-2004, Deadwood Dick
    - Season 2003-2004, She'll Find Her Way Home
    - Season 2003-2004, She'll Find Her Way Home Contracts
    - Season 2003-2004, She'll Find Her Way Home Expenses
    - Season 2003-2004, She'll Find Her Way Home Research
    - Season 2003-2004, She'll Find Her Way Home Sales
    - Season 2004-2005
    - Season 2004-2005, Bios and Artists
    - Season 2004-2005, Artists' Bios
    - Season 2004-2005, Reviews
    - Season 2004-2005, Bubbling Brown Sugar
    - Season 2004-2005, Bubbling Brown Sugar Study Guide
    - Season 2004-2005, Jelly's Last Jam
    - Season 2004-2005, Seven Guitars
    - Season 2004-2005, Sophisticated Ladies
    - Season 2004-2005, Sophisticated Ladies Study Guide
    - Season 2004-2005, Sweet Thunder
    - Season 2005-2006
    - Season 2005-2006, Artists' Bios
    - Season 2005-2006, Reviews and Thank You Letters
    - Season 2005-2006, Little Willie Armstrong Jones
    - Season 2005-2006, Mahalia Jackson: Standing on Holy Ground
    - Season 2005-2006, Mahalia Jackson: Standing on Holy Ground Study Guide
    - Season 2005-2006, Seven Guitars
    - Season 2005-2006, Sing Black Hammer
    - Season 2006-2007
    - Season 2006-2007, Artist Bios
    - Season 2006-2007, Blues in Jazz Waters
    - Season 2006-2007, A Civil Divorce
    - Season 2006-2007, Healthy Black Family or Separation of Blood
    - Season 2006-2007, Healthy Black Family or Separation of Blood Research
    - Season 2006-2007, Healthy Black Family or Separation of Blood Study Guide
    - Season 2006-2007, In the Midnight Hour
    - Season 2006-2007, In the Midnight Hour Artists' Bios
    - Season 2006-2007, In the Midnight Hour Study Guide
    - Season 2006-2007, Relativity
    - Season 2006-2007, Relativity Study Guide
    - Season 2006-2007, Sarafina!
    - Season 2006-2007, Sarafina! Artist's Bios
    - Season 2006-2007, Sarafina! Contracts
    - Season 2006-2007, Sarafina! Contracts and Expenses
    - Season 2006-2007, Sarafina! Study Guide
    - Season 2006-2007, The Separation of Blood Cast Info
    - Season 2006-2007, The Separation of Blood Study Guide
    - Season 2007-2008
    - Season 2007-2008, Ain't Misbehavin'
    - Season 2007-2008, Good Black Don't Crack
    - Season 2007-2008, Journey of the Spirits
    - Season 2007-2008, Journey of the Spirits Study Guide
    - Season 2007-2008, Lavendar Lizards and Lilac Landmines: Layla's Dream
    - Season 2007-2008, Lavendar Lizards and Lilac Landmines: Layla's Dream Artist's Bios
    - Season 2007-2008, Lavendar Lizards and Lilac Landmines: Layla's Dream Study Guide
    - Season 2008-2009
    - Season 2008-2009, Among the Best
    - Season 2008-2009, Clean Drums
    - Season 2008-2009, Clean Drums Study Guide
    - Season 2008-2009, Diane's Heart Dries Out Still More
    - Season 2008-2009, Diane's Heart Dries Out Still More Study Guide
    - Season 2008-2009, Evidence for the Defense and Prosecution, National Consortium on Racial and Ethnic Fairness
    - Season 2008-2009, Evidence for the Defense and Prosecution Contracts
    - Season 2008-2009, Reachings and Pain in My Heart
    - Season 2009-2010
    - Season 2009-2010, Celebration of Absolam Jones
    - Season 2009-2010, Excerpt from Rob Penny's Pain in My Heart
    - Season 2009-2010, Radio Golf
    - Season 2009-2010, Raisin
    - Season 2009-2010, Raisin Bios
    - Season 2009-2010, Raisin Study Guide
    - Season 2009-2010, Raisin, Greensburg Tour
    - Season 2010-2011
    - Season 2010-2011, Harriet Tubman Loved Somebody
    - Season 2010-2011, Mahalia Jackson: Standing on Holy Ground
    - Season 2010-2011, Traces
    - Season 2010-2011, Bios
    - Season 2010-2011, Reviews
    - Season 2011-2012
    - Season 2011-2012, House that Carol Built
    - Season 2011-2012, Ma Rainey's Black Bottom
    - Season 2011-2012, Ruby: Salt of the Earth/ Samson & Delilah
    - Season 2012-2013, Good Black Don't Crack
    - Ensemble Theatre Production, Stories about the Old Days Directed by Vernell A. Lillie, 1992
    - Ensemble Threatre Production, Over Forty Directed by Dr. Lillie, 1996
    - Production Records, Undated
    - Other Blank Forms, Undated
    - Audition Forms, 1975-2003
    - Audition Forms, 2004-2009
    - Audition Forms, Undated
    - Audience Feedback Forms, c.1979-1997
    - Audience Feedback Forms, Undated
  - Poems and Script Segments, Undated; 8.
    This subseries includes poems, script segments, and other creative materials that may or may not have been used by the Kuntu Repertory Theatre in their productions. Dr. Lillie and Rob Penny often produced dramatic collages with Kuntu Repertory Theatre that weaved published and unpublished poetry, monologues, and dialogues together. Some of these materials may have been used to produce collages or as content for Dr. Lillie's drama and literature courses.
    The subseries consists of poems alphabetized by the last name of the author, materials used for theatre classes or other performances, poems written by Rob Penny, poems with no known author or title, collages of poems, and source materials from book excerpts.
    - Authored poems, A-J, Undated
    - Authored poems, K-Z, Undated
    - Authored poems in a collection, Undated
    - "Connection," poetry magazine, Undated
    - Contemporary Black Drama, course material, Undated
    - Contemporary Black Drama, course material, Undated
    - Kindergarten-4th grade performance materials, Undated
    - Rob Penny poems, Undated
    - Rob Penny poems, Undated
    - Rob Penny poems, Undated
    - Rob Penny poems, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Collages of Poems, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
    - Source materials from book excerpts, Undated
- Subject Files (forthcoming), II.
- Workshops, Classes, and Events (forthcoming), III.
- Audio/Visual Recordings (forthcoming), IV.; The contents list for the Audio/Visual Recordings series of this collection is still in-process. There are several hundred audio and video recordings on cassettes and reels. For more information about this series, please contact Archives & Special Collections.
- Photographs, 1975-2011; V.
  Photographs in this collection document Kuntu productions, research for productions, events, workshops, members, and associated groups and individuals. Types of photographs include black and white and color prints, negatives, contact sheets, and slides created primarily between 1975 and 2011. They are arranged first by topic, then chronologically or alphabetically. Photos of productions, events, workshops, and those used for research are arranged chronologically. Photos of members, associated individuals and groups, and headshots are arranged alphabetically by last name or name of group. Oversized materials are noted and housed separately.
  NOTE: Born digital photographs are still in process.
  - Productions, 1975-2011; 1.
    - Little Willie Armstrong Jones, c. 1975
    - The River Niger, 1976
    - Slow Lives on a Humdrum, 1976
    - Slow Lives on a Humdrum, 1977
    - Good Black Don't Crack, c. 1977
    - Diane's Heart Dries Out Still More, c. 1978
    - A New Vision, A Better Tomorrow, 1978
    - What Happens to a Dream Deferred, 1979
    - What Happens to a Dream Deferred, c. 1979
    - Freeman, 1979
    - Ain't No Stopping Us Now and Summer Program, 1980
    - Unidentified Performance, Penn State Altoona, 1980
    - Diane's Heart, 1981
    - Zora: the Darktown Strutter, c. 1981
    - Love to All, Lorraine, 1984
    - Raisin in the Sun, 1984
    - Who Loves the Dancer, 1985
    - Royal Relations, 1985
    - Lift Every Voice and Sing?, c. 1986
    - In Splendid Error, 1986
    - Steal Away, 1986
    - To Be Young, Gifted, and Black, 1986
    - Pain in My Heart, 1987
    - Reachings, 1987
    - When the Chickens Come Home to Roost, 1987
    - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, 1987
    - Dilemma of a Ghost, 1988
    - Still I Rise, 1988
    - Long Time Since Yesterday, 1988
    - Reflections: Rob Penny's Forum in Flight, c. 1989
    - The Meeting, c. 1989
    - Two Can Play, 1989
    - Amen Corner, 1990
    - Crawford Grill Presents Billie Holiday, c. 1990
    - Union Station, 1991
    - Clean Drums, 1991-1992
    - Clean Drums Cast, 1991-1992
    - Shakin' the Mess Outta Misery, 1992
    - Good Black Don't Crack, 1992
    - Among the Best, 1993
    - Diane's Heart Dries Out Still More, 1993
    - Crawford Grill Presents Billie Holiday, 1993
    - Black Pittsburghers, 1994
    - Little Willie Armstrong Jones, 1994
    - Evolution of Jazz, 1994
    - Evolution of Jazz: From the Fields to the Urban Night Clubs, scrapbook, 1994
    - The Miracle Church, 1994
    - Roads of the Mountaintops, 1995
    - Tribute to Ruby Bridges and Evolution of Jazz at New Orleans Heritage Festival, 1996
    - Boppin' with the Ancestors, 1995
    - Flyin' West, 1995
    - Killin' and Chillin' in the Hood, 1996
    - Traces, 1996
    - The Trial of One Short-Sighted Black Woman Versus Mammy Louis and Safreeta May, 1996
    - Over Forty, 1997
    - Miss Dessa, 1997
    - Tambourines to Glory, 1997
    - Resurrection of Lady Lester, 1998
    - Blues for an Alabama Sky, 1998
    - Sacred Ground, 1998
    - Lifting, 1999
    - Keepers of the Dream, c. 1999
    - Papa's Blues, 1999
    - Sing Black Hammer, 1999
    - Zora: The Darktown Strutter, 2000
    - Nefertari Rising, 2000
    - Indigo Blues, 2000
    - Crawford Grill Presents Billie Holiday, Dowes on 9th, 2000
    - Mahalia Jackson, 2001
    - Fortunes of the Moor, 2001
    - Tap Dance Kid, 2001
    - Murderer on the Hill District, 2001
    - Killing Me Softly, 2002
    - The Conjure Man Dies, 2002
    - Hieroglyphic Graffiti, 2002
    - Sherlock Holmes and the Hands of Othello, 2002
    - A Love Song for Mumia, 2002
    - Cryin' Shame, 2003
    - She'll Find Her Way Home, 2003
    - Ashes to Africa, 2003
    - Dark Cowgirls and Prairie Queens, 2004
    - Deadwood Dick, 2004
    - Jelly's Last Jam, 2005
    - Little Willie Armstrong Jones, 2005
    - Production photographs, 2005
    - Seven Guitars, 2006
    - In the Midnight Hour, 2006
    - Mahalia Jackson, 2006
    - Sarafina!, 2007
    - Ain't Misbehavin', 2008
    - Raisin, 2010
    - House that Carol Built, 2011
    - Unidentified Productions: 17 folders, c. 1970s-90s, some undated
  - Events, Workshops, and Research, 1980-2009; 2.
    - Summer Youth Employment Program and Unidentified Performance, c. 1980
    - August Wilson Day, Pittsburgh City Council, September 21, 1987
    - [Creative Visions], c. 1988
    - Kuntu Trip to Jelly's Last Jam in New York City, c. 1993
    - Promotional Slides, c. 1998
    - 25th Anniversary Party, 1999
    - Dedication of William Stargell Statue at PNC Park, 2001
    - Bob Gore Going Away Party, c. 2002
    - [Rob Penny Funeral Procession], 2003
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre and City of Pittsburgh Exhibit at City County Building, 2005
    - National Black Theatre Festival, 2009
    - Kuntu Writers Workshop, Undated
    - Lorraine Hansberry, Research and Display Photographs, Undated
    - Conroy Education Center, Undated
  - Members and Associated Groups and Individuals, c.1960-2005; 3.
    - Sybil Berry, Undated
    - Victoria L. Bowser-Collins, 1999
    - Marta Effinger, Tiffany Ellis, and Ardener Taylor, 1992
    - Freedom Theatre, c. 1988
    - Bob Gore, Undated
    - Bob Gore and Don Marshall, 1988
    - BJ Grier, Undated
    - Valerie Lawrence, 1985, 1989, Undated
    - Eileen Morris, 1990s-2001
    - Joe Morton with Kuntu Repertory Theatre, c. 1976
    - Other Theatre and Dance Companies, Undated
    - Rob Penny, Undated
    - Quantum Theatre, Undated
    - Vivian Reed, c. 2004
    - August Wilson and Marta Effinger, University of Pittsburgh Honors Convocation, 1992
    - August Wilson, Mark Clayton Southers, Vernell Lillie, c. 2003
    - Unidentified Events and Individuals, Undated
    - Vernell Lillie and Rob Penny, c. 1993
    - Vernell Lillie, c. 1980-2000, Undated
    - Vernell Lillie, 1994-1998, Undated
    - Eileen Morris, Undated
    - Youth at City Hall, unknown event, c. 1990
    - Rockwell International C.G.I., 1973-1974
    - Photographs, costuming, Undated
    - Photographs, c. 1980-c. 2000
    - Group photographs, c. 1980-1990
    - Photographs, Kuntu members, c. 1980-2000s
    - Photographs, possible rehearsal, c. 1990
    - Aurora Productions Pageant, c. 1990
    - Unidentified photographs, c. 2002
    - Unidentified photographs, Undated
    - Unidentified neighborhood, demolition photographs, c. 1960
    - Photograph and program collage posters, c. 2005 (Mapcase 27-5, Oversize 5)
  - Headshots, 4.
    - Last names, A-B, Undated
    - Last names, C-E, Undated
    - Last names, F-G, Undated
    - Last names, H-K, Undated
    - Last names, L-M, Undated
    - Last names, N-S, Undated
    - Last names, T-Z, Undated
    - Billy Harper Quintet, c. 2000
    - Unidentified headshots, Undated
- Administrative Records (forthcoming), c. 1975-2013; VI.
- Memorabilia and Artwork (forthcoming), VII.
- Electronic Records (forthcoming), VIII.